Guide to the Reston Times photograph collection, 1970-1980
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Reston Times photograph collection
1970-1980
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
James F. Kirby
C0140
4.25 linear feet (9 boxes)
The collection is comprised of negatives for photographs taken by various photo journalists working for the Reston Times. The collection also includes published and unpublished photographs. The negatives are dated between 1970 and 1980. The negatives are from a variety of communities activities in Reston during that time, including school events, sporting games and community festivals.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Jim Kirby on July 14, 1989.
Historical Information
The Reston Times is one of two local newspapers that are circulated in the Reston area. The newspaper is privately owned by the Fairfax Times a company that also owns several newspapers in the Northern Virginia area. Some of those newspapers include the Annandale Times, Burke Times, Chantilly Times, Fairfax Times, Gainesville Times, Loudoun Times-Mirror, Springfield Times and several others.
The Fairfax Times was created in 1963, when the company founder, Arthur Arundel, purchased the 165-year-old Loudoun Times-Mirror in Leesburg, Virginia. The company is now run by his son, Peter Arundel, who worked in politics and CBS Newsradio before joining the family company. Since Peter Arundel has taken control the company has started or acquired newspapers in Fairfax, Culpeper and Prince William counties, launched the websites, founded the national advertising division and expanded print offerings to an annual calendar of over 50 niche publications.
Jim Kirby worked as a photogapher for the Reston Times and lives in Reston, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The collection is comprised of negatives for photographs taken by various photo journalists working for the Reston Times. The collection also includes published and unpublished photographs. The negatives are dated between 1970 and 1980. The negatives are from a variety of communities activities in Reston during that time, including school events, sporting games and community festivals.
Series one Negatives is the only series in this collection. The series of negatives cover different community events. Some of the negatives are photographs of local people, other are of accidents that occurred in Reston. The final folder of box nine contains a few proofs. The proofs are of photographs of John Warner and Elizabeth Taylor. There is no information to explain the meeting other than it was in the collection and must have occurred in the Washington/Northern Virginia area. The folders are arranged chronologically.
Arrangement
Organized into one series.
Series 1: Negatives, 1970-1980 (Box 1-9)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The Special Collections and Archives also holds the Planned Community Archives and other personal papers and organizational records that document Reston, Virginia and other planned communities.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Reston (Va.)--Photographs.
Subjects:
Schools--Virginia--Reston--Photographs.; Sports--Virginia--Reston--Photographs.
Document Types:
Negatives.; Photographic prints.
Contents List
- Series 1: Negatives, 1970-1980
  This series is comprised of negatives from the Reston Times during the 1970s and into 1980. The negatives are photographs from different community activities such as school events, sporting games and community festivals. The folders are arranged chronologically.
  - Festivals, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Community, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Community Buildings, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Community Activities, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Communities Activities, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - People, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Community, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - School Events, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - School Events, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Community, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Events, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jewelry, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Events, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dulles and Other Places, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - School, Strikes and Other Events, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sports, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Crash, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sport and Other Events, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Winter, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Spring, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Spring, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Summer, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Summer, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Summer, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Summer, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fall, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fall, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fall, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fall, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Winter, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Winter, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Winter, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Winter, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Winter, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Winter, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Winter, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Spring, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Spring, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Spring, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Spring, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Summer, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Summer, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Summer, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Summer, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Winter, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Winter, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Winter, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Winter, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Spring, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Spring, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Spring, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Summer, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Summer, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Summer, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Summer, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Fall, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Fall, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Fall, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Fall, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous: proofs and negatives, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 4)